<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="E21702E9-BDEB-4C28-AC87-18E105479D23">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120219" date="2012-02-19 11:05:43 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>A Precipitous Path</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>I&#x2019;ve never used OSX so the joy of getting my hands on a shiny (albeit second hand) Macbook Pro was cut rather short by my inability to accomplish the most basic of tasks. I must admit I was a bit underwhelmed. I was expecting (and rightly so since several colleagues are huge Apple advocates) a more, err, user friendly experience. Is it just me or is it particularly difficult to move and organise Windows (why can you only resize from the bottom right-hand corner)?&#xD;Anyhow, enough winging, I managed to overcome my OSX prejudices and get on with the matters at hand. I should mention that I did start with a brief(ish) web based proof of concept so I had an idea of what the layout would be and how the code would fit together. I decided to split the front-end (Cocoa objective c stuff) from the back end calculations so I could put these in a separate C++ library. The thinking behind this was that I could knock the library out in a relative small amount of time and it would minimise the amount of Objective C I would need to write. In practice, however, I actually lost some of the useful date/time utilities that Objective C would have given me and ended up having to hand roll some of these in C++, so probably negating any gains I was hoping to make. To be honest Objective C wasn&#x2019;t the massive headache I thought it would be. Once you get a handle on properties and the strange syntax then you can get going fairly quickly.&#xD;Getting to grips with the various Cocoa frameworks and Xcode is, however, quite time consuming. You need to read the documentation, run through a few examples and then re-read the docs again. Working with navigation, tabbar and tableview controllers can be a chore so best to find a close example from the Apple developer website and use this as a starting point.&#xD;I would love to say it has only taken me a week to write the app but it&#x2019;s taken the best part of 3 months and I haven&#x2019;t finished. One of the main problems is trying to achieve things too quickly. There is no magic way of speeding up the learning process (well not for me anyway). I found that I would often sit down at around 9:00pm after making the dinner / getting the kids in bed etc. and find myself rushing to achieve something when really I should have spent more time learning and understanding. I managed to wangle a weekend away without the kids and this is, undoubtedly, where I made the most progress. I would recommend to anyone in a similar position to take the time off work (if at all feasible) and spend one or two solid weeks of developing as this is probably the equivalent of a man month or more when split over the occasional hour here or there.</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Thursday, 20 October 2011&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
